Zhiyu Fan

Ph.D Candidate @ National University of Singapore

Email: zhiyufan@comp.nus.edu.sg Address: 15 Computing Drive, Singapore Webpage: https://zhiyufan.github.io

Biography and Research Interests

My research interests lie in the intersection areas of software engineering and large language models to steer future-oriented AI-centered autonomous software development and maintenance. I'm also interested in exploring relevant techniques to develop AI-tutoring systems to ease the teaching workload for computer science education. My research on autonomous software development has attracted public interest (>1 million views on Twitter, >2.1k stars, and daily/weekly trending on GitHub), and the AI-tutoring system has been deployed in NUS and adopted by other universities for teaching propose.

Education

• National University of Singapore Ph.D Candidate., School of Computing Singapore 2019.08 – 2024.10 (expected)

Thesis: Program Repair for Program Education Advisor: Professor Abhik Roychoudhury

• Southern University of Science and Technology B.E., Computer Science and Engineering

ShenZhen, China 2015.09 – 2019.07

Advisor: Professor Shin Hwei Tan

Publications(* Co-first author, # Corresponding author)

AutoCodeRover: Autonomous Program Improvement
 Yuntong Zhang, Haifeng Ruan, Zhiyu Fan, Abhik Roychoudhury
 International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA), 2024

Oracle-guided Program Selection from Large Language Models
 Zhiyu Fan, Haifeng Ruan, Sergey Mechtaev, Abhik Roychoudhury
 International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA), 2024

- ITS: Experience of Linking Software Engineering and Programming Teaching
 Zhiyu Fan, Yannic Noller, Ashish Dandekar, Abhik Roychoudhury
 arXiv, 2024
- Concept-based Automated Grading of CS-1 Programming Assignments
 <u>Zhiyu Fan</u>, Shin Hwei Tan, Abhik Roychoudhury
 <u>International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA)</u>, 2023
- Automated Repair of Programs from Large Language Models
 Zhiyu Fan, Xiang Gao, Martin Mirchev, Abhik Roychoudhury, Shin Hwei Tan
 International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), 2023
- Verifix: Verified Repair of Programming Assignments
 Umair Z. Ahmed*, Zhiyu Fan*, Jooyong Yi, Omar I. Al-Bataineh, Abhik Roychoudhury
 ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), 2022
- A Systematic Evaluation of Problematic Tests Generated by EvoSuite <u>Zhiyu Fan</u> <u>Student Research Competition at ICSE</u>, 2019

Services

- Reviewer for TSE 2023, SIGCSE 2024, TOSEM 2024
- PC Member for APR Workshop @ ICSE 2024

Awards and Honors

• NUS SoC Research Incentive Award

| • NUS SoC Research Achievement Award | 2023.01 |
|--|---|
| • NUS Research Scholarship | 2019.08-Present |
| • Bronze Medal in ACM SRC@ICSE 2019 | 2019.06 |
| • Outstanding Graduate Thesis Award of SUSTech | 2019.06 |
| • Outstanding Graduate of SUSTech | 2019.05 |
| • ACM SIGSOFT CAPS Grants | 2019.04 |
| • ACM SIGSOFT SRC Travel Award | 2019.03 |
| • First Prize in National Student Contest of Software Testing | 2018.11 |
| Teaching experience | |
| • CS2040S: Data Structures and Algorithms Teaching Assistant | NUS 2024.01 – 2024.04 |
| • CS3213: Foundations of Software Engineering Head Teaching Assistant | $\begin{array}{c} {\rm NUS} \\ 2023.01-2023.04 \end{array}$ |
| • CS3213: Foundations of Software Engineering Teaching Assistant | NUS 2022.01 – 2022.04 |
| • CS4211: Formal Method for Software Engineering Teaching Assistant | $\begin{array}{c} {\rm NUS} \\ 2020.08 - 2020.11 \end{array}$ |
| • CS304: Software Engineering Teaching Assistant | $\begin{array}{c} {\rm SUSTech} \\ 2019.03-2019.06 \end{array}$ |
| • CS303A: Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Teaching Assistant | $\begin{array}{c} {\rm SUSTech} \\ 2019.03-2019.06 \end{array}$ |
| • CS102A: Java How to program Teaching Assistant | $\begin{array}{c} {\rm SUSTech} \\ 2016.09-2017.01 \end{array}$ |

Last update: July 3, 2024